[The Ingenious One]
[Episode 9 The Heart-breaking Past]
I thought you would be the one
talking up there.
The plan is set.
It doesn't matter who comes forward.
It's rare that Mingyu cares about our family affairs so much.
This is a good time to train him.
We can also take this chance
to get to know the merchants.
You never blink at any catastrophe.
I really admire your charisma, Chairman Su.
Once the deeds of 80,000 catties of raw silk are sold,
the silk price will not rise
but fall by 30%.
So it can stabilize the silk market in Nandu.
If the raw silk can be sent back successfully,
all problems will be solved.
If not...
Peculiar tactics always help people
win a battle or make a fortune.
Only those who dare to gamble can win.
Qian,
we've already given up a lot of interest.
Why are they still hesitating?
Do as Lady Su said.
It'll definitely work.
Guys.
Guys!
As you all know,
we, the Su family, used to ship silk
all by water.
But now, the Cao Sect
has stopped all the cargo ships from Yangzhou to Nandu.
I think you are worried that
it'll be hard to honour the deeds
if the raw silk can't be sent into the city.
But in business,
the first is to keep your word,
the second is to be faithful,
and the last is to seek profits.
Our Su family has been royal suppliers for a century,
and we're always trustworthy.
We chose water transport
because delivering by post roads took a longer time
and cost more.
But the recent rise in the silk price
balances the cost.
The post roads are the best choice now.
Of course,
you might think the bandits are rampant on the post roads.
We Su family has paid a lot
to hire the prestigious Four Armed Escort Agencies
to ensure the safety of the goods.
And I, Su Mingyu,
will go escort the goods in person this time.
I swear with my life.
Young Master,
please don't talk recklessly again.
Mr. Qin,
could you read out the end of the deed
to everyone?
Yes.
The deal is closed with a cash purchase.
No registration, and free exchange.
Well...
The raw silk price in Nandu has been soaring,
just because someone's storing it to sell it
at a higher price.
We merchants all speak from a business standpoint.
So Chairman Su has no intention of accusing you.
But the Chamber of Commerce is responsible for keeping the price down.
So Chairman Su decided that
the deeds could be traded freely.
Now, our price is still two taels per catty.
-I want it... -I want one.
-Me too... -Me too...
[Deed]
[Two taels of silver per catty of raw silk. 80,000 catties in total. Delivery within 15 days.]
The deeds of 80,000 catties of raw silk
have been mostly sold.
Once this stuff's gaining ground,
the price of raw silk will surely plummet
by around 30%.
Master,
we spent over 100,000 taels of silver
and stored 50,000 catties of raw silk.
It's time to dump it.
We can make half the profit if we dump at this time.
It’s quite safe for our Cao Sect.
You would make a name for yourself in this battle.
And in the future, no one in Nandu
will dare to look down
on our Cao Sect, including that Tang Xiao.
You know what I want.
Master,
we have ample time.
Why don’t we achieve it step by step?
The plan of deeds is already the Su family's final counterattack.
We'd better just give up
this Pyrrhic victory.
Ding Yi,
I'm thinking about something.
Su Huairou is a business genius,
but this plan of deeds
is not what she normally uses.
Last night,
Qian Rong invited Yun Xiang into Su's Mansion.
It’s him.
70% of the deeds of 80,000 catties of raw silk
have been sold in one day.
The Su family really lives up to its commercial reputation.
The more we sell, the greater the loss.
This is probably the biggest bet
our Su family has ever made.
Don't worry, Sister.
This time, I'd risk my life
to bring the raw silk back.
You can’t go.
Sister!
Not until this family calamity
did I realize how selfish I was.
I didn’t take any responsibility for the Su family before.
And I’ve been learning martial arts since my childhood.
The escort will be absolutely safe this time.
Stop messing around.
I’ve staked all the lives
of our Su family
to fight for the last chance.
I won't risk your life again.
Chairman Su,
Mr. Su just promised to escort in person
in front of
so many merchants.
If he goes back on his word now,
what will those merchants think?
What worries them the most today
is that this batch of raw silk can’t be shipped to Nandu,
and their deeds can't be honoured.
If Mr. Su goes to escort the goods in person,
on one hand,
it can show the confidence and determination of your Su family.
On the other hand, it can assure the merchants
that these deeds can be honoured in time.
In this case, you can both reassure people
and stabilize the price.
I know, of course.
I understand.
You're of the same blood.
How about this?
I'll send "Ten Taels of Gold" and Shu Yanan
to escort Mr. Su there.
Both of them are top martial arts masters
who risk their lives in the martial world.
Their escort
will keep Mr. Su safe and sound.
Yes, Sister.
Just rest assured.
Even though I'm not an invincible martial arts master,
I can still protect myself
when something happens.
But are you not gonna have any guards by your side?
It's said the people of the Cao Sect have been trying
to get rid of you.
Qi Tianfeng is stocking up on raw silk right now.
His ambition is evident.
Chairman Su, I believe you already know
who he's targeting and trying to bring down.
My lady,
Ding Yi, the steward of Qi Tianfeng, is outside,
asking to see Yun Xiang.
Steward Ding of the Cao Sect has come.
He wants to see you.
Ding Yi?
It's about time he came.
How about this?
Just follow our previous arrangement,
and leave the rest to me.
Master Qi has prepared wonderful wine and dishes at Xianfu Restaurant.
We'd like to invite you to come.
May I have the chance
to enjoy this meal, too?
Master Qi only invited Mr. Yun.
Please forgive me for not making a decision by myself.
Don't make it difficult for him.
I'll just go with him.
Beware of tricks.
That would be more interesting.
Mr. Ding, please lead the way.
This way please, Mr. Yun.
Qian,
what should we do now?
In this situation,
Mr. Yun went to see Qi Tianfeng alone.
Young Master,
I'm afraid you've thought too much.
How can we figure out
the thoughts of someone like Yun Xiang?
You and I have fought several times.
And we finally meet each other today.
In a battle between two armies,
there's no need for the commanders-in-chief to charge at the front.
Fragrant and soft as silk.
It's puffer meat.
Yes.
I've been suffering from a chronic illness.
Fortunately, I got a secret remedy.
Make soup with puffer meat
and heal with its slight poison.
How's the effect?
I've recovered 70%.
The Iron Hand Demon with 70% power
is already invincible in Nandu.
My internal injury was not caused by anyone else,
but by my overly fierce palm technique
which has hurt my meridians.
There's also a fatal flaw in the strange moving technique
you just used, I guess.
Judging from your breath, you don't look like
someone with a powerful internal force.
I guess it consumes a lot of internal force,
or it can't last long.
My moving technique can only last 10 breaths.
You told me your fatal flaw yourself.
Aren't you afraid I'll kill you?
To kill me,
you didn't have to go through all this trouble.
Master Qi,
let’s just get to the point.
You remind me
of how Wen Cong used to be when he just came to Nandu.
I'm afraid it’s inappropriate
to mention Mr. Wen so flippantly.
Did the Yuntai Sect send you to take revenge?
Yes,
or no.
Is it also your idea
to let the Su family sell the deeds?
Exactly.
You should know
I will never let the raw silk be delivered to the city.
Business is similar to martial arts.
If you use too much force,
it might backfire.
I heard the cruel Taotie was carved
on the bronze ware of the previous dynasty.
Taotie likes eating people.
But due to a miscalculation, it was stuffed
to death.
Master Qi,
the Su's business is not that easy to swallow in one gulp.
Am I the only one who resembles the Taotie?
If the Su family surrenders now,
they'll only lose their commercial reputation,
or at most the title of the royal supplier.
But now, by selling deeds,
they're betting on the Su family's century-old foundation.
You
pushed the Su family to their doom.
You'll wait until both the Cao Sect and the Su family
are about to lose,
so you can reap the benefits easily, right?
Don’t you also wanna kill two birds with one stone, Master Qi?
You wanna destroy the Su family and me,
and replace us.
I think we'd better call it a day.
When everything's clear,
we'll meet again.
Okay.
[Liansheng House]
I knew you were an orphan.
But I thought you grew up in a charity.
I was lucky and met a good person.
But what will happen to those kids?
I can't imagine.
Anyway, listen to me.
You can't find those kids
all by yourself.
He's coming.
The light went out.
I thought you all left me behind.
How's it? Where's Miss Ke?
Didn't you point the finger at her idleness?
She went to hire the head dealer and servants early in the morning.
Are you satisfied, Boss?
This is the right way.
If you have nothing else to say,
don't get in the way of our drinking.
The Su's trade caravan will set off tomorrow.
This time
we've assembled the best armed escort agencies in Nandu,
whose members all have their unique techniques,
but I still think
we need a commander with unparalleled martial arts skills.
Jin,
in my heart,
you're the perfect choice.
According to the news spreading out there,
for the Su's trade caravan,
over ten gangs of bandits along the river have gathered.
In this fight,
how many people have I gotta kill?
As usual,
10 taels of gold per person.
What’s the current price of silk in Yangzhou?
One tael of silver for three catties of silk.
And what’s the price of the Sus' deeds?
Two taels of silver per catty of silk.
The Su family has sold deeds of 80,000 catties of raw silk.
After this delivery, they're gonna earn
at least 100,000 taels.
But even if I fight so hard and break my sword,
do you think I can earn 1,000 taels?
Then Jin, how about you name a price?
I don't want any remuneration.
But you must get all the children
of Jishan Hall back.
How can I find them?
Backed by the Yuntai Sect,
you can definitely figure out a way.
Why are you looking at her?
I already know you so well.
Maybe I can find them.
But if I bring back such a large group of orphans,
how should they be accommodated and raised?
And who will take care of them?
You.
You pay to rebuild the charity
and hire a teacher to teach them how to read
when they're old enough for that.
Those overachievers will find their way naturally,
while the others
can stay in this Liansheng House and work here
so that they won't starve to death.
What?
Do you think the price is too high?
Too high to reach.
Then just cut the crap,
and find someone else.
Commander Jin!
Pack your bags now.
Cheers!
You let Jin name such a high price to me.
What if I refuse?
You would agree no matter what price he asked for.
Ten Taels of Gold and I must both be there
for the Su family's business this time,
because you need to let Qi Tianfeng know
you've staked everything you have.
Have you told him all my arrangements?
I just wanna help him get those children back.
I'll keep my mouth shut about what I'm not supposed to say.
You're a fast learner in how to coerce people
in a smart way.
It's just an eye for an eye.
It's not that I didn't want to help.
But we need to prioritize the tasks, right?
So you do have some human touch.
Where have you been today?
Why are you back so late?
I went to Qi Tianfeng's banquet.
Qi Tianfeng?
Qi Tianfeng already knew
it was my idea to use the raw silk deeds.
He just wanted to sound out the facts.
And I also wanted to know
what his next move would be.
If he starts to dump the raw silk now,
we can only see him
escape unscathed.
Will he
dump it now?
He wants more than these penny profits.
What is this?
I wanted to test his martial arts skills.
And I got this by accident.
If he didn't come for revenge,
then he's stirred up trouble
just to do what Wen Cong failed to finish back then
and control the business world in Nandu.
Isn't it the usual tactic of the Yuntai Sect?
Master,
it will take a great deal of money
to raise the price of the deeds.
We have nowhere to borrow money now.
[Luo]
What's wrong with you?
You, Young Master Xiang, never blink at any disaster.
If you panic even a little,
that means something big has happened.
Tell me about it. Maybe I can help you.
Yes, you can.
Can you leave me alone? Thank you.
Look at this character.
Luo...
The Luo family's village?
He’s from the Luo family's village!
I kept observing him during the meal.
Still, I was almost cheated by him.
This is the evidence.
Yun Xiang is here for revenge.
His personal revenge.
[Cao Sect]
I didn't expect it to be you.
It was quite powerful,
but not accurate.
You remain cool in the face of shock.
You're really not the crying little girl
you used to be.
The Altair Swordplay is the Shu family's orthodox technique.
Unfortunately, it's not top-class.
Girl,
if you try again,
I'm afraid I won't be interested.
Sit down and have some tea.
Maybe we can talk about the past.
Why are you laughing?
I'm laughing at my useless sympathy
for not killing you back then.
Wen Cong took over Shu's Armed Escort Agency.
He ordered me to kill you all.
My Godfather is dead.
Don't talk nonsense about him.
He destroyed your whole family,
while he adopted you as his daughter.
He wiped away the blood
and blamed everything on me alone.
I've been holding back for revenge over the past decade.
I don't wanna wait any longer.
If you slander my Godfather ever again,
I will kill you
even at the cost of my life!
Enough.
You can't kill me.
Stop wasting time.
Besides,
you're not the one to fight in the end.
I guess you came here
for that thumb ring tonight.
Am I right?
Exactly.
But you will pay with your blood one day.
They're long dead.
Who else knows the truth?
Forget about it.
I'll let you go.
Send him a message.
The secret about this thumb ring.
The secret?
What?
You've been staying by his side,
while you didn't even know
he had such a big secret hidden in him.
Did you stay up all night?
Where are you going? Wait a second.
Give me your hand.
For what?
Do not lose it again.
How did you get it?
Did you go to meet Qi Tianfeng?
What did he tell you?
Shouldn't you have asked me
if he gave me a hard time first?
You shouldn't have acted without my permission.
If you ruined my plan,
we'll lose everything.
How heartless you are.
When you went to Qi Tianfeng's place,
did he give you a hard time?
Qi Tianfeng asked me to tell you something.
He said, so long as you stopped working with the Su family,
he'd tell you the whole story
you wanted to know.
I've told you everything.
No need to say goodbye.
Fortunately, the world is wide.
And we don't need to meet again.
I'm not here to say goodbye to you.
My plans have never failed.
Why don't you believe me?
You don't believe in my strategies,
or me.
You
are not trustworthy.
But after I heard those stories,
I can understand you now.
You survived out of 313 people,
who were brutally murdered.
if you're not vigilant or sort of cold-blooded,
how can you resist the fear in your heart
and endure the nightmare every night?
Honestly, I'm quite envious
of you sometimes.
You and I are both survivors.
But your heart is warm.
You still have the guts to love.
Love your friends,
and those children.
You dare to try something impossible.
I'm really envious.
Thanks. I'm flattered.
No,
I'm the one who should say thank you.
Thank you.
Alright...
The armed escorts are about to set off.
Come back safely.
Look.
This knot is so tough.
It will never get loose again.
[Su]
The Su's trade caravan
even outshines the Grand Coordinator's deployment to suppress the bandits.
Su Mingyu really led the team in person.
Jin Biao and Shu Yanan are also among them.
But the bandits of all the gangs have gathered,
with the help of the martial arts masters from our sect.
Even if these escorts boast their unique skills,
it’s not that easy to transport the raw silk
into the city.
Those bandits
are no more than a motley crew.
But we must make sure nothing goes wrong.
Then I'll choose 60 more good fighters from our sect.
Our men in the sect
all follow us through fire and water.
Give them enough rewards before their departure,
and let them settle their families down.
Okay.
How long has this stone beast been here?
Since our Cao Sect started to thrive
and moved here.
It's too old.
We should get a new one.
That guy didn't tell me his name, and he refused to leave.
He insists on meeting Mr. Mo.
How are you doing, Mr. Kang?
How's your injury?
Did we not open the main door today?
I took a different road for something important, of course.
Can a rascal have anything important to talk about?
Mr. Mo said
he had nothing to do with you anymore.
Why don't you ask him one more time?
I can never talk about the assassination
of Ten Taels of Gold again.
But those kids who have been sold
are such poor things.
Kang Qiao,
you go arrange this.
Make sure to be considerate and keep the kids safe.
OK.
Mr. Mo,
I’m here to tell you that
I can pay back the 30,000 taels of silver I owe you.
Pay back?
How?
Did you bring the silver?
15 fast cargo ships,
plus the boatmen.
300 mu of prime paddy fields,
and more than 20 high-quality stores.
The properties along the river, and a lobby of the Cao Sect's headquarters.
What do you think?
If the raw silk can’t be sent into the city,
the Su family will fall.
If it's transported into the city,
the Cao Sect will lose all their money.
Qi Tianfeng's estate
cannot be owned by you no matter what.
You're right.
I've spared no effort to set up a series of schemes
just to help you get something, Mr. Mo.
Mr. Mo,
whether the raw silk can be delivered to Nandu
is not up to me,
the Su family,
or Qi Tianfeng.
So...
It's all up to you, Mr. Mo.
Master,
Master Qi is here,
asking to talk to you about a big deal.
Master Qi,
you’ve borrowed
from almost all the banks in Nandu.
Why did you come to our Guanghui Bank so late?
For the last battle,
I need to turn to the No.1, of course.
How much do you wanna borrow? And what's the interest?
1% interest for all the other banks in Nandu.
But I'll give you 3%.
I can't give you more, or it will break the rule.
You've already borrowed money from all the banks in Nandu.
Are you talking about the rule now?
I'd like to say something.
You've fought against the Su family to this extent
not for profit, right?
What do you think?
I thought
this is your sink-or-swim battle.
If you win, you can replace them
and be the head of Nandu Chamber of Commerce,
with great wealth and a prominent reputation.
I heard the bandits are rampant on the post roads.
I’m afraid the Su family can't get their raw silk into the city.
But the overall situation in the city is still uncertain.
The Su family issued the deeds of 80,000 taels of raw silk
to lower the price of raw silk,
which was raised by you.
Master Qi, you wanna borrow so much money
just to raise the price of the deeds too.
Mr. Qi, am I right?
So how much profit do you want, Mr. Mo?
I don't want any of it.
I only want 10% of the Cao Sect's monthly income.
10% of the income...
Everyone says that you are a ruthless profiteer.
Today, I saw you
even going further.
What's wrong with a merchant seeking profit?
I promise you
10% of the income.
Great!
You can borrow as much money as you like.
I can give you the key to the vault.
But Master Qi,
what will you give me as collateral?
Just tell me what else you want, Mr. Mo.
Master Qi,
I've given you everything I have.
Of course, you should mortgage something valuable with me.
I think,
the estate of your Cao Sect is quite suitable.
[Guanghui Bank]
Mr. Qi,
as the old saying goes,
do not forget me when you succeed.
Mr. Mo, let's say goodbye here.
OK.
Master,
how much did you borrow?
Let's talk about it when we're back.